Yunxiang Zhang

RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am currently a Ph.D. student researching computer graphics at New York University, with over two years of experience in developing advanced graphics algorithms and systems. My research interests are at the intersection of real-time rendering, perceptual computer graphics, and virtual/augmented reality. I enjoy combining theoretical insights from physical, biological, and cognitive sciences with machine learning tools to solve challenging real-world problems.

EDUCATION

New York University Brooklyn, NY 11201, USA

Sep 2022 - Present

Apr 2016 - Aug 2018

Mar 2020 - Jun 2020

Doctor of Philosophy in Computer Science and Engineering

Advisor: Prof. Qi Sun

The Chinese University of Hong Kong Hong Kong SAR, China

Master of Philosophy in Information Engineering Aug 2020 - Aug 2022

Thesis: Towards Physically Realistic Human-Environment Interaction in Virtual and Augmented Reality

Advisor: Prof. Dahua Lin

Shanghai Jiao Tong University Shanghai, China

Master of Engineering in Electronics and Communication Engineering Sep 2017 - Mar 2020

Thesis: Similarity-Based Approach to Neural Network Pruning

Advisor: Prof. Bingbing Ni

École Polytechnique Palaiseau 91128, France

Diplôme d'Ingénieur in Computer Science (double-degree program between SJTU and EP)

Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Shanghai, China Bachelor of Engineering in Information Engineering Sep 2013 - Aug 2017

EXPERIENCE

Research Intern, Vector Institute Toronto, ON M5G 1M1, Canada

Supervisor: Prof. Nicolas Papernot

Research Intern, LTCI Télécom Paris Paris 75013, France

Supervisor: Prof. Samy Blusseau, Prof. Santiago Velasco-Forero, Prof. Isabelle Bloch, and Prof. Jesús Angulo Apr 2018 - Aug 2018

Software Development Intern, SNCF Saint Denis 93200, France

Supervisor: Loïc Hamelin Jun 2017 - Sep 2017

PUBLICATIONS

Toward Optimized VR/AR Ergonomics: Modeling and Predicting User Neck Muscle Contraction

SIGGRAPH 2023 Conference Proceedings Paper

Yunxiang Zhang, Kenneth Chen, Qi Sun

• Force-Aware Interface via Electromyography for Natural VR/AR Interaction

ACM Transactions on Graphics (SIGGRAPH Asia 2022) Paper

Yunxiang Zhang, Benjamin Liang, Boyuan Chen, Paul M. Torrens, S. Farokh Atashzar, Dahua Lin, Qi Sun

CaPC Learning: Confidential and Private Collaborative Learning

International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR 2021) Paper

Christopher A. Choquette-Choo*, Natalie Dullerud*, Adam Dziedzic*, Yunxiang Zhang*, Somesh Jha, Nicolas Papernot, Xiao Wang

Exploiting Channel Similarity for Network Pruning

IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology (TCSVT 2023) Paper

Chenglong Zhao, Yunxiang Zhang, Bingbing Ni

· Max-plus Operators Applied to Filter Selection and Model Pruning in Neural Networks

International Symposium on Mathematical Morphology and Its Application to Signal and Image Processing (ISMM 2019) Paper Yunxiang Zhang, Samy Blusseau, Santiago Velasco-Forero, Isabelle Bloch, Jesus Angulo

* Equal contributions, authors ordered alphabetically

AWARDS

New York University

SoE Fellowship (2022 – 2023)

The Chinese University of Hong Kong

Postgraduate Scholarship (2020 – 2022)

Shanghai Jiao Tong University

SPEIT Academic Excellence Scholarship (2015 – 2016)

Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Ardian Scholarship (2014 – 2015)

PROFESSIONAL SERVICES

Review for AAAI 2021, IEEE ISMAR 2022, IEEE VR 2023, IEEE ISMAR 2023

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant, Virtual and Augmented Reality (CS-GY 9223), New York University Teaching Assistant, Final Year Project (IERG 4998/4999), The Chinese University of Hong Kong 2022 Fall

2020 - 2022

SKILLS

• **Programming**: C/C++, Python, C#, Java, CUDA, Matlab

• Tools: PyTorch, TensorFlow, OpenGL, Libigl, Eigen, Git, CMake, OpenMP

• Software: Blender, Unity, Photoshop, Premiere Pro, Illustrator, Matlab, Mathematica, MeshLab

• Language: Mandarin, English, French